worldbankgroup.org 2002-06-07

# The World Bank Group | Privacy Policy

**I. Introduction**  
Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us . Because we gather certain types of information about the users of the World Bank's sites and services, we want to ensure that you fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. This privacy policy applies to all World Bank sites - that is all sites within the "worldbank.org" domain name. 

**II. What Information Does the World Bank Collect?**  
If you are just browsing on the World Bank's site, we do not collect any personal information regarding your use of the site. However, if you register for an email newsletter, buy a book or join a discussion group, you will be asked for personal information, such as your name and email address. When you register, the World Bank sets a cookie, a small bit of code stored on your hard drive that enables you to manage your subscriptions and online profile. By setting this cookie the World Bank will remember you the next time you visit and won't have to bother you by asking questions you have already answered (like address information). 

In addition, the World Bank also records your IP address, which is the Internet address of your computer, and information such as your browser type and operating system. This information helps us learn about the geographical distribution of our website visitors and the technology they use to access our site. This information is never connected with the personal information you supply to us if you register on our website. 

**III. What Does the World Bank Do with the Information?**  
The Bank uses the information for three primary purposes:  

  * To make the site easier for you to use by not having to enter information like your address more than once. 
  * To help you quickly find information that is relevant to you based on your interests. 
  * To help us create site content areas most relevant to you. 
  * To confirm your purchases and registrations on the site. 

The Bank uses a contractual fulfillment vendor to process and ship orders, and a credit card processing service to bill users for goods they purchase. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

**IV. What If I Don't Want to Share My Information?**  
Registering on our site is optional. If you choose not to register or provide personal information, you can still use the World Bank's web site. However, you will not be able to purchase items or receive email newsletters. The Bank views the customer information that it collects as a trusted asset for which we take great care in not misusing. 

If you register for a newsletter, forum, consultation, or conference the Bank will not share, sell, distribute or rent your information to anyone. If you enter into a transaction on our [Publications](http://publications.worldbank.org/) web site, your information will not be shared unless you indicate that you would like to receive information from [UN agencies](http://www.unsystem.org/), multilateral banks or international organizations with whom we occasionally share mailing address information. However, we will never share your e-mail address with these organizations. 

**V. Security**  
The World Bank Group employs a range of technologies to protect the information maintained on our systems from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction. 

**VI. How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions or concerns about the World Bank Privacy Policy, please contact us at [feedback@worldbank.org](mailto:%20feedback@worldbank.org). 

**VII. Notification of Changes**  
If there are any changes to this privacy policy, we will post them on our home page at: [www.worldbank.org](http://www.worldbank.org/) and in our [Publications](http://publications.worldbank.org/) check-out so that you are completely aware of how the changes will affect you. 

**Glossary**  
**Cookie-** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Each web site can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Once the user has closed the browser the cookie will no longer be accessed during that session. 

**IP Address\- **When your web browser or email application requests a web page or email from another computer on the Internet, it automatically gives that computer the address where it should send the information. This is called your computer's "IP address." (IP stands for "Internet protocol.") For many users accessing the Internet from a dial-up Internet service provider (ISP), the IP address will be different every time you log on. The World Bank does this to learn about the geographical make-up of its web site traffic.
